Akifumi Wachi

💌 akifumi.wachi@gmail.com | 🌐 website | 😱 GitHub | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🞓 Google Scholar

Research Interests

My research interests lie primarily in reinforcement learning, and span the entire theory-to-application spectrum from foundational advances all the way to deployment in real systems. Especially, I am interested in safe reinforcement learning to optimize an agent policy under safety constraints.

Work Experience

Senior Research Scientist

Sep 2022 - present

LINE Corporation

Research Scientist

Apr 2018 - Aug 2022

IBM Research AI

Research Assistant

Apr 2017 - Mar 2018

National Institute of Communication Technology (NICT)

Research Assistant

Apr 2016 - Mar 2018

Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA)

EDUCATION

Mar 2021 Ph.D. in Computer Science at University of Tsukuba

Mar 2018 M.S. in Aeronautics and Astronautics at University of Tokyo

 $Mar\ 2016$ B.S. in Aeronautics and Astronautics at University of Tokyo

Publications

- 1. Akifumi Wachi, Yunyue Wei, Yanan Sui, "Safe Policy Optimization with Local Generalized Linear Function Approximations" Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.
- 2. Ran Iwamoto, Ryosuke Kohita, Akifumi Wachi, "Polar Embedding" The SIGNLL Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL), 2021.
- 3. Daiki Kimura, Masaki Ono, Subhajit Chaudhury, Ryosuke Kohita, Akifumi Wachi, Don Joven Agravante, Michiaki Tatsubori, Asim Munawar, Alexander Gray, "Neuro-Symbolic Reinforcement Learning with First-Order Logic" Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Short paper, 2021.
- 4. Ryosuke Kohita, Akifumi Wachi, Daiki Kimura, Subhajit Chaudhury, Michiaki Tatsubori, Asim Munawar, "Language-based General Action Template for Reinforcement Learning Agents" Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), Findings, 2021.
- 5. Ryosuke Kohita, Akifumi Wachi, Yang Zhao, Ryuki Tachibana, "Q-learning with Language Model for Edit-based Unsupervised Summarization" Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020
- 6. A. Wachi, Y. Sui, "Safe Reinforcement Learning in Constrained Markov Decision Processes", International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020
- 7. A. Wachi, "Failure-Scenario Maker for Rule-based Agent using Multi-agent Adversarial Reinforcement Learning and its Application to Autonomous Driving", International Joint Conference on Arti-

- ficial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2019
- 8. <u>A. Wachi, Y. Sui, Y. Yue, M. Ono, "Safe Exploration and Optimization of Constrained MDPs using Gaussian Processes"</u>, AAAI conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2018
- 9. R. Takahashi, R. Sakagami, <u>A. Wachi</u>, Y. Kasai, S. Nakasuka, "The Conceptual Design of a Novel Simple and Small-sized Mars lander", IEEE Aerospace Conference, 2018
- 10. R. Sakagami, R. Takahashi, <u>A. Wachi</u>, Y. Koshiro, H. Maezawa, Y. Kasai, S. Nakasuka, "Integral Design Method for Simple and Small Mars Lander System Using Membrane Aeroshell", Acta Astronautica.
- 11. <u>A. Wachi</u>, R. Takahashi, R. Sakagami, Y. Koshiro, Y. Kasai, S. Nakasuka, "Feasibility Study for Mars Landing with Small Space Probe", AIAA SPACE and Astronautics Forum and Exposition (2017 AIAA SPACE Forum), 2017.
- 12. R. Takahashi, <u>A. Wachi</u>, R. Funase, S. Nakasuka "Hazard Avoidance Control Using Stochastic Optimization for Mars Safe Landing", 31st International Symposium on Space Technology and Sciences, 2017.
- 13. <u>A. Wachi</u>, "Low-Thrust Trajectory Design to Improve Overall Mission Success Probability Incorporating Target Changes in Case of Engine Failures", 31st International Symposium on Space Technology and Science (ISTS), 2017. **Nominated to Best Student Paper Award: First Prize (General Chairperson Award)**
- 14. <u>A. Wachi</u>, N. Ozaki, S. Nakasuka, "Fault-Tolerant Low-Thrust Trajectory Design with Backups for Multiple Targets", 20th IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace (ACA), 2016. **Nominated to the Best Student Paper Award: First Prize.**

PATENTS

I have over 10 filed patents which can be found here: https://patents.justia.com/search?q=akifumi+wachi

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Conference Reviewing (Program Committee Member)

- ICML 2021 2023
- NeurIPS 2021 2023
- ICLR 2022 2023
- IJCAI 2020 2023
- AAAI 2020 2024
- ACL 2020 2021, 2023
- EMNLP 2020

Journal Reviewing

- ACM Transactions on Evolutionary Learning and Optimization (Associate Editor)
- IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence

Awards

Dean's Award (second prize), from Faculty of Engineering, The University of Tokyo, 2018

- Best Student Paper Award, First Prize (General Chairperson Award), Joint Conference: 31st ISTS, 26th ISSFD, and 8th NSAT, 2017, http://www.ists.or.jp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/31_Prize-List.pdf
- Best Student Paper Award (First Prize), IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace (ACA), 2016, http://aca2016.ngcaerospace.com/studentaward.php

FELLOWSHIP

- Financial support to participate in Thirty-second AAAI conference on Artificial Intelligence by Society for Promotion of Space Science (SPSS), \$1.5K, February, 2018
- Financial support to participate in International Astronautical Congress (IAC) by the Japan Society for Aeronautical and Space Sciences (JSASS), \$2.5K, September, 2017
- Go Global Scholarships 2016 Short Study Abroad Scholarships: the University of Tokyo, \$1K/month, 3 months, 2016
- Fellowship of the Leading Graduates Schools Program: Global Leader Program for Social Design and Management by the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology in Japan, \$1K/month, 1 year, 2016
- Financial support to visit California Institute of Technology (Caltech) and NASA/JPL by the University of Tokyo, \$1.0K, February, 2014

Last updated: August 2, 2023